Guide to the Richard Foreman and Kate Manheim Papers MSS.152
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Oversize
  - Oversize Series III.B: Production Materials, Productions directed but not written by Richard Foreman.
    - "Samuel's Major Problems" directed by Jerry Mouawad at Imago, Portland Oregon. Oversized press and publicity materials., 1996 (Box 52, Folder 1359)
    - Symphony of Rats" publicity poster for production directed by Jerry Mouawad at Imago Theatre., undated (Box 52, Folder 1361B)
  - Oversize Series III.D: Miscellaneous Production Materials
    - Theatre de la Bastille stage plans. Production not designated. Plans drawn in 1982. (Folder 2 Left)
    - Theatre National Opera de Paris stage plans. Production not designated. Plans drawin in 1983. (Box 52, Folder 1367)
    - Cinema Theatre le Dejazet stage plans. Production not designated., undated (Folder 3 Left)
    - Theatre Femina in Bourdeaux. Production not designated., undated (Box 52, Folder 1369)
  - Oversize Series IV.A: Photographs of Richard Foreman's Productions
    - "The Birth of the Poet" 13 pages of black and white contact sheets of Rotterdam production. Photographed at by Leo van Velzen, 1984 (Box 53, Folder 1385)
    - "Book of Splendors I" 4 black and white contact sheets and four black and white prints by Sergio Gaudenti., undated (Box 53, Folder 1390)
    - "Cafe Amerique" 3 black and white contact sheets by Bob van Dantzig, Amsterdam., undated (Box 53, Folder 1406)
    - "Cafe Amerique" 1 black and white contact sheet and 4 color prints by Nicolas Treatt, Paris., undated (Box 53, Folder 1411)
    - "Classical Therapy" 14 black and white contact sheets and one 4x5 negative by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 53, Folder 1412)
    - "The Cure" black and white print by Pamela Duffy, 1986 (Box 53, Folder 1416)
    - "Dr Faustus Lights the Lights" 4 black and white contact sheets and 4 black and white prints by Nicolas Treatt, Paris., undated (Box 53, Folder 1433A)
    - "Dr Selavy's Magic Theater" black and white contact sheet by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 53, Folder 1433B)
    - "Evidence" black and white contact sheets by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 53, Folder 1447)
    - "Hotel Fuck" or "Paradise Hotel" 12 color contact sheets by Tina Barney. (Box 53, Folder 1471)
    - "Madness and Tranquility" black and white contact sheets by Robert del Tredici., 1973 (Box 54, Folder 1498)
    - "Maria del Bosco" color contact sheets by Tina Barney., 2002 (Box 54, Folder 1499)
    - "My Life, My Death..." 4 black and white contact sheets by unknown photographer and the resulting photograph postcard promoting the play., ca 1985 (Box 54, Folder 1519)
    - "Now that Communism is Dead..." 8 color contacts by Tina Barney., 2001 (Box 54, Folder 1520)
    - "Pandering to the Masses" black and white prints by Max Waldman., undated (Box 54, Folder 1530)
    - "Particle Theory" black and white contact sheets by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 54, Folder 1534)
    - "Total Recall" black and white prints by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 54, Folder 1575)
  - Oversize Series IV.B: Photographs of Richard Foreman
    - Black and white contact sheet of Richard Foreman with friends including Amy Taubin, Michael Snow, Yvonne Rianer, Ernie Gehr, Jessica Harper, Kate Manheim and Power Booth. Photographed by Babette Mangolte., undated (Box 54, Folder 1604)
    - 1 black and white portrait of Richard Foreman by Frederic Ohringer, part of Frederick Ohringer Photographs People project., undated (Box 54, Folder 1607)
  - Oversize Series IV.C: Photographs of Richard Foreman
    - Black and white contact sheet by Babette Mangolte. Images document the Paris end of the New York Telephone Event., 1972 (Box 54, Folder 1615)
  - Oversize Series VIII.B: Publications by Richard Foreman
    - File v. 4 n.4. Includes "The Start of a 27 Volume Analysis of 'Everything'", 1980 (Box 55, Folder 1694)
    - Champagne, Lenora. The American Book Review review of "Plays and Manifestos" by Richard Foreman., 1980 (Box 55, Folder 1695B)
    - Two and Two July 1985. Includes "Putting the DEMAND into the Work" (Box 55, Folder 1697)
    - Love and Science matted cover art, undated (Box 55, Folder 1706)
  - Oversize Series VIII.C: Interviews with Richard Foreman
    - l'art vivant October 1973. "Richard Foreman: Entretien" (Box 55, Folder 1708B)
    - Bomb Spring 1994. Eric Bogosian interviews Richard Foreman. (Box 55, Folder 1729)
    - The Village Voice 16 August 1994. "Avant-Guardians: Foreman Meets LeCompte" (Box 55, Folder 1730)
    - "Stumbling and Falling: An Interview with Richard Foreman" by Andrew Quick, New York 11 June 1997. (Box 55, Folder 1732)
  - Oversize Series VIII.D: Projects and performance pieces
    - A Bunch of Experimental Theatres of New York Inc Connecticut College American Dance Festival. Summer theater workshop program, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 1742)
    - The Philip Glass Ensemble program for "North Star." Program notes by Richard Foreman., 1978 (Box 55, Folder 1745)
    - "Show People" at Exit art, oversize press original of New York Times coverage. Research copies in folder 1749, 2002 (Box 55, Folder 1750)
  - Oversize Series VIII.E: General Press
    - Washington Review v.3 n.6, "New Theatre", 1978 (Box 55, Folder 1762)
  - Oversize Series VIII.F: Critical writing about Richard Foreman
    - Scarpetta, Guy. "American Connection" Art Press international, 1976 (Box 55, Folder 1783)
    - "Emergency" nos 5 and 6., 1999 (Box 55, Folder 1804)
  - Oversize Series IX: General Theater Related Material
    - "Futura" program, 1973 (Folder 6 Left)
    - "Palm Casino Review" at Bauwerie Lane Theatre, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 1834)
    - Invitation to party celebrating the birth of Sean (Leopold) Chapell Mekas at Judson Memorial Church., 1975 (Box 55, Folder 1838)
    - Nagrin, Lee Swezea. Exhibition poster., 1978 (Box 55, Folder 1877)
  - Oversize Series X.A: Award certificates and photographs
    - Village Voice Off-Broadway Award "OBIE", Special Citation for "Elephant Steps", 1969-1970 (Box 56, Folder 1951)
    - Village Voice Off-Broadway Award "OBIE", Special Citation for the Ontological-Hysteric Theatre., 1972-1973 (Box 56, Folder 1952)
    - Village Voice OBIES, "Rhoda in Potatoland", 1976 (Box 56, Folder 1953)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters photograph, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 1959)
    - Pen Awards, 2001 (Box 56, Folder 1964)
  - Oversize Series X.B: Award Press
    - OBIE press, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 1969)
  - Oversize Series X.D: Fundraising and Benefits for the Ontological Hysteric Theater
    - Black and white photographs of Richard Foreman's parents. These photographs by Ralph Gibson were a prize from a 1976 benefit for "Strong Medicine"., 1977 (Box 56, Folder 1981)
    - Photo-album. Held the images of Richard Foreman's parents. Includes explanation of the event and images., 1977 (Box 56, Folder 1982)
    - Photographs on paper of "Maria del Bosco" cartoon narrative and of Richard Foreman in front of a "Luogo + Bersaglio" banner in Italy. Auctioned as part of a benefit for the Ontological-Hysteric Theatre., undated (Box 56, Folder 1985)
  - Oversize Series XI.C: Miscellaneous Correspondence
    - Requests to work with Richard Foreman, 1978 (Box 57, Folder 2000)
  - Oversize Series XI.D: Political materials
    - Not In Our Name. New York Times full page ad., 2002 (Box 57, Folder 2007)
  - Oversize Series XI.E: Printed Matierals
    - Scene Saint-Denis no. 27, 1980 (Box 57, Folder 2010)
    - Cover of Village Voice 16 August 1983. Purchased in France (Box 57, Folder 2011)
  - Oversize Series XII.D: Family related documents
    - Leslie Foreman's diploma from C.W. Post College of Long Island University. 8 June 1963 (Box 57, Folder 2059)
  - Oversize Series XIII.A: Kate Manheim's scripts and notes.
    - "Strong Medicine" 3 ring binder., undated (Box 57, Folder 2211)
  - Oversize Series XIII.E: Kate Manheim's Other Projects and Performances
    - "Kate Manheim: Painter, actress" paintings and collages at Court House Gallery., 1996 (Box 57, Folder 2290B)
    - "Composite" featuring three posters: 1. A drawing my a cast member's child 2. Penguin Touquet poster 3. Joack Smith drawing/advertisement in the SoHo news., undated (Folder 15)
    - Heiner Muller performance, "Medee-Meteriau" script with annotations. taped together, end to end., 1984 (Box 57, Folder 2299)
    - Heiner Muller performance, "Medee-Materiau" annotated script, taped end to end., undated (Box 57, Folder 2300)
    - Heiner Muller performance, "Medee Materiau" annotated script, taped end to end., undated (Box 57, Folder 2301)
  - Oversize Series XIII.F: Kate Manheim, Interviews and General Press
    - "Kate Mannheim: Self-expression takes many forms for a successful actress who grew up in Paris" p. 30 in Passion, the Magazine of Paris., 1987 (Box 57, Folder 2313)
  - Oversize Series XIII.G: Kate Manheim, General Theater Related Material
    - New York Buckley School's Christmas program., 1970 (Box 57, Folder 1324)
    - New York Shakespeare Festibal, "The Chronicles of King Henry VI" at Delacorte Theater, program., 1970 (Box 57, Folder 1325)
    - Byrd Hoffman Foundation and School. Program, "Overture" at 147 Spring St., 1972; playbill "A letter for Queen Victoria" at Anta Theatre, 1973. (Box 57, Folder 1337)
    - Film Society of Lincoln Center, New York Film Festival 10th annual schedule, 1972; New York Film Festival poster, 1974; "New Directors/New Films" 1975, 1972-1975 (Box 57, Folder 1339)
    - Nonas, Richard. "Enclosures" at 10 Bleecker St., 1972 (Box 57, Folder 1347)
    - "The Trust" and "Our Lady of Late" at 57 Laight St. Performance by Meredith Monk, Ray Kelley, Collin Walcott, Edward Effron and William Dunas., 1972 (Box 57, Folder 2352)
    - Howard, Richard. "Untitled Subjects" reading at Bergman Gallery., undated (Box 57, Folder 2388)
  - Oversize Series XIII.H: Kate Manheim, Awards and Grants
    - OBIE award for "Rhoda in Potatoland", 1976 (Box 57, Folder 2409)